Giulio V. Blanc
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Artist Files, 1920-1995, undated, Series 3:; (boxes 1-8; 6 linear ft.)
  - Jorge Pérez-Castaño (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Photo transparencies, 1978-1979, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Jose A. Piedra (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Victor Piedra (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material and exhibition announcement, 1982, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Marcelo Pogolotti (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1944 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Photo transparency, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Fidelio Ponce de Leon (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material and birth certificate, 1950, 1967 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Letters, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Writings and articles by Fidelio Ponce de Leon and Giulio Blanc, 1953, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcements, catalogs, 1938, 1949, 1992 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1938, 1944, 1949, 1966, 1992-1993, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, 1934-1935, 1937, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Eudardo Ponjuán (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1993 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - René Portocarrero (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1944, 1947, 1965, 1980 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Writings, draft of essay on René Portocarrero by Giulio Blanc 1993 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - News paper clippings and articles, 1941, 1944, 1985, 1993, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, 1938-1950, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Alberto Pozo (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1982 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Ernesto Pujol (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material, 1993, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Letters, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Press releases, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Miscellany, exhibition checklist, 1993-1994, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Ciro Quintana (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1993 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Carlos Rafael (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1995 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Teodoro Ramos Blanco (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Letter, 1937 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1931, 1941, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Felix Ramos (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clipping, 1982 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Sandra Ramos (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1993 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Arnaldo Ravelo (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Letter, 1983 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1983 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Miscellany, exhibition list, 1983 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Ravenet (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcement and catalog, 1953, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Manuel Revuelta (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1988 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Angel R. Rios (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcements and newsletter, 1994 (Box 6, Reel 5481)
  - Enrique Riverón (see Appendix for an itemized list of printed material) (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Biographical material and resume, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1957-1994, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Letters and postcards, 1969, 1981-1990, 1995-1996, (3 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Writings, draft writings by Enrique Riverón and transcribed interview by Giulio Blanc [Incomplete], 1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Notes, handwritten notes by Giulio Blanc and list of artwork, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - El Arte y el Amor en Montparnasse, by Armando Maribona (copy), 1950, (3 folders) (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1924-1934, 1944, 1980, 1987, undated (Box 6, Reel 5481)
    - Articles by Enrique Riverón (authored or illustrated), 1920-1931, 1947 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Audio material, interview with Enrique Riverón, audio cassette tape, 1984 [Untranscribed, Spanish] (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs of Enrique Riverón and of artwork, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, page of Bacardi Art Gallery exhibition catalog, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Rodriguez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1977 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Arturo Rodriguez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1977-1989, 1993 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalogs, 1979, 1987, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1986-1994, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - José Miguel Rodriguez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1982 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Mariano Rodriguez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Writings, draft essays on Mariano Rodriguez by Giulio Blanc, 1992, 1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1958 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1944-1949, 1958, 1990 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, 1945, 1969 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Rocio Rodriguez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Alexis Rodriguez-Duarte (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1995 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, exhibition check list and other material, 1994, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Leopoldo Romañach (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photocopies of art work, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - José Rosabal (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1972 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Lydia Rubio (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letter, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Writings, draft article on Lydia Rubio by Jill Levine, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1981-1994, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Gilberto Ruiz (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1981-1982, 1985, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Writings, drafts of article on Gilberto Ruiz by Giulio Blanc and Juan Espisona, 1983, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1983-1995, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1985, 1993, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, front cover of magazine and price list, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Baruj Salinas (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1981-1983, 1992, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Press releases, 1983, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1982, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Baruj Salinas, catalogue, 1982 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photo transparencies, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Emilio Sanchez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1985-1986, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Notes, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1970-1992, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalogs, 1971, 1974, 1977, 1985, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Press releases, 1980, 1985 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1980, 1985, 1992-1997 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs, 1980, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Mario Sanchez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1981-1982, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Articles, 1982 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Thorvald Sanchez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Tomás Sánchez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, 1990, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Writings, draft essay on Tomás Sánchez by Giulio Blanc, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Notes, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, 1990, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, promotional material from Weiss Sori Fine Art and copy of invitation to panel discussion, 1993, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Zilia Sanchez (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Articles, exhibition catalog, poster, 1984, 1991 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs, 1978, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Veronica Scharf Garcia (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1993 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Haydee and Sahara Scull (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1983, 1995 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Writings, draft article on the Scull sisters by Giulio Blanc, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1953, 1994, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1953, 1956-1983, 1992, 1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs, 1983, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Ernesto Selgas (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs, 1988 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Jesus Selgas (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1988 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1988-1989, 1993-1994, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1991, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Press release, 1988 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Daniel Serra-Badúe (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1979, 1984-1986, 1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1964, 1967, 1971-1979, 1985, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalogs, 1980, 1983, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Press release, 1984 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1985, 1992 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Photographs and photo transparencies, 1965, 1975, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, greeting card with artwork by Serra-Badué, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Guillermo Serrano (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalog, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Juan Sí (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1995, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Writings, drafts and published articles by Giulio Blanc and Juan Sí, 1992-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Notes and transcribed interview [Incomplete], undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement and catalog, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1991-1992, 1995 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, large envelope and press release from Ollantay Art Center, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Jorge Luis Sícre (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1982, 1992 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Paul Sierra (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material and resume, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters and postcards, 1988, 1992-1994, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1991-1995 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalogs, 1990-1991, 1995 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1982-1986, 1993 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Miscellany, laser color copy of book cover with Sierra's art work, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Daniel del Sol (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Xul Solar (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1993 (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Dolores Soldevilla (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcement, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Susan Sori (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Biographical material, 1987, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Letters, 1991, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Exhibition announcements and invitations, 1981-1982, 1990, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1981-1982, 1985, undated (Box 7, Reel 5482)
  - Rafael Soriano (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letters, 1980 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1977, 1981, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1979-1992, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Miscellany, poster, 1968 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Gabriel Sorzano (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcement, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Leandro Soto (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Writings, draft copy of article on Leandro Soto by Giulio Blanc, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalogs, 1992 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Press release, 1994 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Photo transparency, 1994 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Miscellany, exhibition list from Weiss-Sori Fine Art, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Amaury Suarez (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1991 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Agusto Tagle (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1973 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Juan Tapia-Ruano (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Patricio Texidor (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Alberto Torre de Alba (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letters, 1993, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Writings, draft article on Torre de Alba by Giulio Blanc, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements and invitations, 1990, 1992 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalogs and pamphlets, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1991 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Ruben Torres Llorca (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1992 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - César Trasobares (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1979-1980, 1991 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1984 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1984, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Miscellany, posters, 1978, 1984 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Gladys Triana (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letters, 1987, 1989 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1974 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition checklist and text, 1987, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Carmen Trujillo (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1993 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Orfilio Urquiola (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Rafael Vadia (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letters, 1990 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition catalogs, 1982, 1988 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1982, 1989, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Miscellany, posters, 1978, 1981 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Andres Valerio (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1982 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1987 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Photograph and photo transparency, 1980-1981, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Gustavo del Valle (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Luis Vega (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material and photo transparencies, 1982 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Fernando Veranes (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material and price list, 1970s (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Ricardo Viera (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letters, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1979-1985, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Photo transparencies, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Juan Pablo Villar (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material and exhibition announcement, 1993, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Pedro Vizcaíno (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Exhibition announcement, 1992 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Maria Nelida Zamora (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Biographical material, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Writings, book chapter, “Artist as Individual” by Maria Nelida Zamora, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Mark Zimmerman (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letter, 1994 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
  - Ricardo Zulueta (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Letters, 1982, undated (Box 8, Reel 5483)
    - Articles, 1987 (Box 8, Reel 5483)
- Exhibition Files, 1977-1995, undated, Series 4:; (box 8; 1 linear foot)
  The following series contains information on exhibitions Blanc curated during his career and includes press releases, draft writings of catalog essays, correspondence, printed material such as exhibition announcements and catalogs, newspaper clippings or articles, photographs, and other related material. Not all exhibitions in this series were curated by Blanc.
  - Treasures of Colonial Days in Cuba: The Romance of an Era (1980), Miami-Dade Public Library System and the Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture, Miami, FL., 1980 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (exhibition announcement and small catalog)
  - The Miami Generation: Nine Cuban American Artists (1983), Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture, Miami, FL., 1984, 1994, undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (project description, announcement for 1994 panel discussion; “The Miami Generation meets the 80s Generation” for Art Miami `94 held at the Miami Beach Convention Center, draft of opening remarks, list of participants, draft of lecture, “The Miami Generation and Latin American Art” by Blanc held at Meridian House, Washington, DC in 1984, magazine articles, and reviews of the exhibition)
  - Cuba: A View from Inside (1985), Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture, Miami, FL., 1985 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (letter by Blanc to editors of the New York Village Voice in response to a review of the exhibition)
  - Cuban Colonial Architecture: Reality and Fantasy (1985), Miami-Dade Public Library, Miami, FL., 1985 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (letter from Blanc to the editor of the Miami Herald in response to review by staff art critic Helen Kohen)
  - Amelia Peláez: A Retrospective (1988), Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture, Miami, FL. 1968, 1984-1988, 1992, undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (9 folders; exhibition guidelines, letters to Blanc from friends and colleagues about the Peláez exhibition, letters to the Museum of Modern Art in New York, letters to the Peláez sisters and Julian Peláez del Cabal and other material)
  - Cintas Fellows Revisited: A Decade After (1989), Metro Dade Cultural Center, Miami, FL., 1977, 1984, 1989, undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (4 folders; exhibition guidelines, NEA grant application, list of participants for 1984 symposium, “Empirical Sources of Metaphor in Modern Cuban Art”, held at the Gross School of the Arts, Rutgers University, list of eligibility requirements for Cintas Fellowship, list of past Cintas Fellowship recipients, list of artworks displayed in the exhibition, exhibition catalogs, newspaper clipping)
  - Cuba-USA: The First Generation (1991), Fondo del Sol Visual Arts Center, Washington, D.C. 1991-1992, undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (3 folders; newspaper clippings, list of reviews and bibliography for exhibition and exhibition catalog)
  - Wifredo Lam and His Contemporaries (1992), Studio Museum in Harlem, New York, N.Y. 1989-1994, undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (8 folders; letters from Studio Museum in Harlem outlining terms of agreement for Blanc and co-curator, Julia Herzberg, letters from Blanc to The Americas Society, Galerie Albert Loeb and others, letters to Blanc and the Studio Museum from Wifredo Lams' widow, Lou Larin-Lam, NEA planning proposal, exhibition checklist, exhibition announcements, press releases, newspaper clippings and other material)
  - Cuban Art: Past and Present (1993), Museum of Art, Fort Lauderdale, FL. (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (2 folders; letters to Blanc regarding catalog essay and letters to Blanc's parents concerning their contribution to the exhibition)
  - De Cuba a Cuba: El Arte Como Puente (1993), Cuban Museum of Art and Culture, Miami, FL., 1993 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (newspaper clippings and exhibition catalog)
  - Latin American Art in Miami Collections (1994), Lowe Art Museum, University of Miami, Coral Gables, FL., 1991-1995, undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    (5 folders; letters to Blanc concerning exhibition, artists' biographical material, press releases and public program announcements, newspaper clippings, color photographs of artwork from the collection of Dr. and Mrs. Francisco Venegas, Miami, FL.)
- Subject Files, 1933-1995, undated, Series 5:; (boxes 8-12; 2.5 linear feet)
  Included are files collected by Blanc on various interests and current events including the controversy surrounding the Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture (Miami) in the late 1980s. The files are broken down into areas such as Letters, Notes, Writings, Printed Material, Photographs, and Miscellany with Printed Material including exhibition announcements and catalogs, newspaper clippings and articles, art journals, and other published material.
  The files are arranged in alphabetical order by either name or subject.
  - The Art Museum, Ft. Lauderdale, FL., undated (Box 8, Reel 5484)
  - Artists in Exile film, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5484)
  - Biennials (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    - Segunda Bienal de la Habana (Havana), 1986 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    - Tercera Bienal de la Habana (Havana), 1989 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    - Cuarta Bienal de la Habana (Havana), 1991 (Box 8, Reel 5484)
    - Quinta Bienal de la Habana: Arte, Sociedad y Reflexión (Havana), 1994 (Box 9, Reel 5484)
    - 19a Bienal Internacional de São Paulo (São Paulo), 1987 (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban art history, 1937-1954, (5 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban art history, pre-1960s, 1944-1959, undated, (6 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban art history, post-1960s, 1963-1994, (14 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban colonial architecture, 1857, 1941-1944, 1986, undated, (6 folders, 1 sol) (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban colonial art, 1950-1962, 1976-1995, (5 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban art exhibitions, post 1960s, 1979-1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5484)
  - Cuban group exhibitions outside of Cuba, pre-1960s, 1944-1958, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban group exhibitions outside of Cuba, post 1960s, 1965-1993, (3 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban group exhibits, pre-1960s, 1955-1955, undated (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban group exhibits, post-1960s, 1965-1995, (9 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban history, 1976-1984, (3 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban literature, 1972-1993, undated, (6 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban Museum of Arts and Culture, Miami, FL., 1980-1994, undated, (22 folders) (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban poetry, 1988 (Box 10, Reel 5485-5486)
  - Cuban revolution, 1959-1983, undated, (5 folders) (Box 11 (hol), Reel 5487)
  - Cuban sculpture, 1944, 1973-1982, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11 (hol), Reel 5487)
  - Cuban social history [neighborhood events], 1975-1984, undated, (4 folders) (Box 11 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - Exhibitions in Cuba, 1937-1958, (3 folders) (Box 11 (hol), Reel 5487)
  - Fondo del Sol Visual Arts Center, Washington, DC, 1988-1995, (3 folders) (Box 12 (pam), Reel 5487)
  - Arte-10, artists' collective, 1981 (Box 12 (pam), Reel 5487)